<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>courses on Sharat Project</title>
    <link>/tags/courses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in courses on Sharat Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 19:51:04 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/courses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Prenatal Bonding</title>
      <link>/courses/prenatal_bonding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 19:51:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/prenatal_bonding/</guid>
      <description>Prenatal bonding occurs when a mother and her baby form a bond while the infant is still in the womb. The mental and emotional state of the mother during pregnancy has an impact on the baby&amp;rsquo;s behavior. Prenatal bonding aids in the delivery of a healthy and intelligent baby.
The session includes Early Brain development Bonding techniques with the unborn baby Stimulation techniques Visualization </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pregnancy Nutrition</title>
      <link>/courses/pregnancy_nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 19:51:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/pregnancy_nutrition/</guid>
      <description>To nourish your body during pregnancy, you must eat nutritious meals and follow a well-balanced diet. As your pregnancy advances, good diet will help you cope with the increased demands on your body. Regular exercise is necessary to maintain a healthy weight and stay active throughout pregnancy. There will be a diet chart available.
The session includes Diet &amp;amp; Nutrition Lifestyle choices that promote health Exercise &amp;amp; weight management Mindfulness &amp;amp; Visualization Breathing exercises </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor and Birth</title>
      <link>/courses/labor_and_birth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 19:50:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/labor_and_birth/</guid>
      <description>This session is designed to assist pregnant women in overcoming their fears about childbirth. You can make your child&amp;rsquo;s birth a memorable event with the correct assistance and information.
The session includes Stages of Labor Pain management techniques Medical procedures Cesarean delivery </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breastfeeding</title>
      <link>/courses/breastfeeding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 19:49:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/breastfeeding/</guid>
      <description>Breastfeeding is a natural talent for both mom and infant. Even though it is the fact that nursing is natural, it is extremely difficult to achieve success in recent years. To provide you with the necessary support and guidance to help you succeed in this process.
The session includes Golden hour after birth Latching positions &amp;amp; techniques How to boost up your milk supply Breastfeeding myths &amp;amp; facts Baby’s behavior &amp;amp; hunger cues Milk Expression &amp;amp; Storage </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postpartum care</title>
      <link>/courses/postpartum_care/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 19:49:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/postpartum_care/</guid>
      <description>The postpartum care session focuses on guiding women&amp;rsquo;s wellness care in the critical weeks following delivery. Anticipatory counseling should start throughout pregnancy, as the postpartum period is critical for the mother&amp;rsquo;s physical and mental recovery. This session will help you prepare for parenthood by identifying your postpartum requirements ahead of time.
The session includes Physical recovery – Early &amp;amp; Later postpartum period Postpartum warning signs Postpartum mood disorders Caring for yourself Postpartum fitness </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newborn care</title>
      <link>/courses/newborn_care/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 19:45:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/newborn_care/</guid>
      <description>The newborn care session for expectant parents helps to build confidence by better understanding the concepts in taking care of their babies during the early stage of parenting.
The session includes Newborn procedures Bathing &amp;amp; Diapering Infant Massage Feeding pattern Sleeping pattern Newborn Warning signs Debunking the myths </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lactation Counseling </title>
      <link>/courses/lactation_counselling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 19:44:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/lactation_counselling/</guid>
      <description>Personalized Consultation sessions for new moms who are struggling with breastfeeding issues. Video consultations available.
Latching issues Milk supply issues Feeding Multiples Premature babies Milk Blebs Blocked Ducts Engorgement Mastitis Thrush Slow weight gain Re-Lactation Expression &amp;amp; Storage of breast-milk All of the above can be resolved with good lactation support; it helps new mothers to breastfeed by offering knowledge and assistance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
